Guide to the Emanuel Fritz Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Emanuel Fritz papers
1912-1914
MS 805
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
The papers are comprised of Fritz's class notes, field work notes and term reports while at the Yale School of Forestry. Also included are Civil Service questions for foresters for 1913.
Fritz, Emanuel, 1886-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Emanuel Fritz, 1976.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains papers of Emanuel Fritz (born 1886), a member of the Yale School of Forestry class of 1914, and later a professor of forestry at the University of California at Berkeley. The papers consist of class notes, notes on field work, examinations, and a report by Fritz dating from his study at Yale. Also included are Civil Service questions for foresters from 1913. The papers were donated to Yale University by Professor Fritz in 1976.
Biographical / Historical
Emanuel Fritz: member of the Yale School of Forestry Class of 1914; later professor of forestry at the University of California at Berkeley.
Forests and forestry; Foresters; Fritz, Emanuel, 1886-; Yale College (1887- ). Class of 1914; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. School of Forestry
- Inventory
  - Yale School of Forestry class papers
    - Forest Economics: class notes, examination, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Silvics: class notes, examination, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Silviculture: class and field work notes, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - "Field Report on Gray Birch and Eastern Hemlock," by E. Fritz, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Forest Engineering and Construction: class notes, examination, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Forest Practice: class notes, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - National Forest Law: class notes, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Practice of Forestry, Western U.S.: class notes, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Civil Service questions, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 10)